# Jun Xing (邢骏)

junxnui@gmail.com, http://junxnui.github.io

#### RESEARCH

My research combines modern concepts in Computer Graphics, Human Computer Interaction and Machine Learning, with broad applications in digital painting, animation, special effects, sculpting, image, and geometry analysis and synthesis, as well as UI/UX design. Now, I am moving my application platform to VR/AR! In particular, I am interested in analyzing the human-centered activities of authoring the various digital contents, and providing online "intelligent" suggestions, via a natural interface, to reduce manual labor while improving quality and performance.

# **EDUCATION**

PhD, Computer Science 2012.09—2016.12

University of Hong Kong, Dept. of Computer Science Advised by Dr. Li-Yi Wei

#### **Bachelor**, Electronic Engineering and Information Science

2008.09 - 2012.06

University of Science and Technology of China (USTC), Dept. of Electronic Engineering and Information Science GPA: 3.85/4.3

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

University of Southern California, postdoc in ICT, with Hao Li, Los Angeles	2017.05-present
Adobe, intern in the Procedural Imaging Group, with Cynthia Lu etc., San Jose	2016.07-2016.09
Autodesk Research, intern in the UI Group, with Rubaiat Habib Kazi etc. Toronto	2016.01-2016.04
Microsoft Research Asia, intern in the Visual Computing Group, with Takaaki Shiratori etc., Beijing	2014.12-2015.04

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Xu Shen, Xinmei Tian, Jun Xing, Yong Rui, Dacheng Tao. Sequence-to-Sequence Learning via Shared Latent Representation. Accept by AAAI 2018.
- Mengqi Peng, Jun Xing, Li-Yi Wei. Autocomplete 3D Sculpting, arXiv:1703.10405 [cs.GR].
- Jun Xing, Rubaiat Habib Kazi, Tovi Grossman, Li-Yi Wei, Jos Stam, George Fitzmaurice. Energy-Brushes: Interactive Tools for Illustrating Stylized Elemental Dynamics. UIST 2016.
- Jun Xing, Li-Yi Wei, Takaaki Shiratori, and Koji Yatani. Autocomplete Hand-drawn Animations. ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG), Proceedings of ACM SIGGRAPH Asia 2015.
- Jun Xing, Hsiang-Ting Chen and Li-Yi Wei. Autocomplete Painting Repetitions. ACM Transactions on Graphics (TOG), Proceedings of ACM SIGGRAPH Asia 2014.

#### MORE RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### Hair Modeling from A Single Image via Neural Network

2017.09—present

Submitted to CVPR 2018

Given an unconstrained hair image, our network can generate sparse hair strands close to the target hairstyle, which can be used as guidance to synthesize dense hair model.

## Mesoscopic Facial Geometry Inference via Deep Neural Networks

2017.07 - present

Submitted to CVPR 2018

We present a method to faithfully reconstruct high resolution facial geometry from a single texture image.

#### **Identity Preserving Face Completion for Large Ocular Region Occlusion**

2017.05-present

Submitted to CVPR 2018

We present a novel deep learning approach to synthesize full face images in the presence of large ocular region occlusions.

### Autocomplete VR painting

2016.07—present

The goal is to handle different types of repetitions in VR painting, including the detail decorative strokes, the surface strokes, and even higher-level scaffold, in a simple and general framework.

# Strip-based Hair Modeling in VR

2017.08-present

We provide a 3D VR authoring interface for immersive interaction with the hair models. Our system combines the flexibility of manual authoring and the convenience of data-driven automation for high quality hair modeling.

#### **Variational Representations for Facial Geometry**

2017.08-present

We explore the nonlinear embedding of facial geometry based on latest advances of variational autoencoder.

# **Interactive Facial Hair Editing and Synthesis**

2017.06-present

Users can design facial hairs of different shapes/lengths/densities via simple sketching, while keeping the style of a target facial hair defined by an exemplar image.

### **PATENTS**

Techniques for Generating Dynamic Effects Animations: US filed by Autodesk (2016)

Stroke Operation Prediction for Three-Dimensional Digital Content: Pending, filed by Adobe (2017)

# **ACADEMIC SERVICE**

Committee Member:

SIGGRAPH 2017 Emerging Technology

Reviewer:

SIGGRAPH Asia 2017; CHI 2017; Computer & Graphics 2017; IEEE Transactions on Cognitive and Developmental Systems 2017; PG 2015, 2016; IEEE Computer Graphics and Applications 2016

# **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

Designer: algorithm, system, UI/UX

Programmer: C/C++, Qt, Python, Java, OpenGL/CV/VR, Unity

Artist: digital painting, hand-drawn animation

#### **AWARDS**

Excellent intern of Stars of Tomorrow Internship Program, Microsoft Research Asia (MSRA)

HKU University Postgraduate Fellowships (UPF), HKU

Outstanding undergraduate, USTC

2012

Outstanding undergraduate research project, USTC

2011

Second prize in Mathematical Contest in Modeling

2011

National Scholarship, Ministry of Education, P.R.China National Inspirational Scholarship, Ministry of Education, P.R.China Outstanding Students Scholarship, USTC 2011 2009, 2010 2008, 2009